Guide to the Fred Eggan Papers 1870-1991
University of Chicago Library
- Series VII: Philippines Files
  - Subseries 7: Tinguian
    - Sub-subseries 1: General
      - Labor, notes, undated (Box 122, Folder 17)
      - Clothing, personal ornament, notes, 1934 (Box 122, Folder 18)
      - Life cycle, notes, c.1934 (Box 122, Folder 19)
      - Likuan, Venancio, autobiographical notes, 1935 (Box 122, Folder 20)
      - Comparative lexical list, undated (Box 122, Folder 21)
      - "Materials for Tinguian-Ilocano Comparative Grammar, " manuscript, 1935 (Box 122, Folder 22-23)
      - Cole, Fay-Cooper, measures, botanical terms, word lists, manuscript, correspondence, notes, 1917-1935 (Box 123, Folder 1)
      - Cole, Fay-Cooper, grammar, word lists, Luzon languages, manuscripts, notes, undated (Box 123, Folder 2)
      - Cole, Fay-Cooper, nouns, verbs, prefix, suffix, manuscripts, notes, undated (Box 123, Folder 3)
      - Cole, Fay-Cooper, valley dialect grammar, word lists, undated (Box 123, Folder 4)
      - Cole, Fay-Cooper, valley dialect grammar, notebook, undated (Box 123, Folder 5)
      - Cole, Fay-Cooper, songs, games, texts, undated (Box 123, Folder 6)
      - Dances, songs, undated (Box 123, Folder 7)
      - Riddles and proverbs, undated (Box 123, Folder 8)
      - Acculturation, notes, undated (Box 123, Folder 9)
      - Factors of change, mission, transportation, communication, schools, medical, political, notes, undated (Box 123, Folder 10)
      - "The Igorots of Mountain Province, " manuscript, undated (Box 123, Folder 11)
      - "Radio Lectures on Anthropology and the People of the Mountain Province, " manuscript, undated (Box 123, Folder 12)
      - Beyer-Holleman Papers, paper no. 143, 145, 180, 182, account no. 22, 30, 42, 46, 51, 55, 66, undated (Box 123, Folder 13)
      - Miscellaneous, clipping, pamphlet, 1936, 1964 (Box 123, Folder 14)
    - Sub-subseries 2: Eggan Field Trip Records
      - Correspondence, family, clippings, 1934-1935 (Box 124, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence, University of Chicago, clippings, 1934-1937 (Box 124, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence, Tinguian correspondents, magazine, 1935-1939, 1949 (Box 124, Folder 3)
      - Field diary, 1934-1935 (Box 124, Folder 4-5)
      - Field diary, Bangued, Abra, July-September1934 (Box 124, Folder 6)
      - Field diary, September-November1934 (Box 124, Folder 7)
      - Field diary, Manabo, November 1934-January 1935 (Box 124, Folder 8)
      - Field diary, January-July1935 (Box 124, Folder 9)
      - Field notebook, 1934-1935 (Box 125, Folder 1-3)
      - Field notebook, Abra notes, 1934-1935 (Box 125, Folder 4)
      - Notebook, undated (Box 125, Folder 5)
      - Expense accounts, 1934-1935 (Box 125, Folder 6)
    - Sub-subseries 3: Ceremonies
      - Patoc, Lumaba, diams, field notebook, 1934 (Box 125, Folder 7)
      - Notes, 1934 (Box 125, Folder 8)
      - Analysis of Tinguian ceremonies, notes, undated (Box 125, Folder 9)
      - Cosmography, seasons, measures, notes, undated (Box 125, Folder 10)
      - Religion, taboos, notes, undated (Box 125, Folder 11)
      - Spirits, sickness, notes, clippings, 1934 (Box 125, Folder 12)
      - Spirit mediums, magic, undated (Box 125, Folder 13)
      - Specialists, weaving, spirit mediums, undated (Box 125, Folder 14)
      - Cole, Fay-Cooper, games, medicines, cures, notes, undated (Box 125, Folder 15)
      - Richardson, A. H., Balbalasang (Tinguian) Vocabulary, notes, undated (Box 125, Folder 16)
    - Sub-subseries 4: Dreams
      - Manuscripts, correspondence, notes, 1934-1957 (Box 126, Folder 1)
      - "Tinguian (and Ilocano) Dreams from Abra Province, Philippines, " manuscript, correspondence, 1957 (Box 126, Folder 2)
      - Areola, Felisa, "Autobiography, " manuscript, correspondence, notes, 1939-1941 (Box 126, Folder 3)
      - Areola, Felisa, dreams, beliefs, notebook, undated (Box 126, Folder 4)
      - Areola, Felisa, [del Rosario], dreams, beliefs, notebooks, correspondence, 1936 (Box 126, Folder 5-11)
    - Sub-subseries 5: Kinship and Social Organization
      - Abra towns, kinship charts, 1934-1935 (Box 126, Folder 12)
      - Genealogies, undated (Box 126, Folder 13)
      - Kinship, notes, clippings, undated (Box 126, Folder 14)
      - Government, correspondence, notes, clipping, undated (Box 126, Folder 15)
      - Masaoay, diary, children, marriage, divorce, notebook, undated (Box 126, Folder 16)
      - Cole, Fay-Cooper, Tinguian genealogies, manuscript, undated (Box C)
    - Sub-subseries 6: Myths, Stories, and Diams
      - Ceremonies, diams, correspondence, informant note books, 1935 (Box 126, Folder 17)
      - Folktales, Lamao, manuscripts, correspondence, newsletters, 1947-1954 (Box 127, Folder 1-2)
      - Og-káy-an, interlinear translation, note book, undated (Box 127, Folder 3)
      - Og-káy-an, text analysis, notes, undated (Box 127, Folder 4)
      - "Iwagianan, " manuscript, notes, undated (Box 127, Folder 5)
      - "Ritual Myths among the Tinguian, " manuscripts, undated (Box 127, Folder 6)
      - Cole, Fay-Cooper, story (Salita), texts, 1909 (Box 127, Folder 7)
      - Cole, Fay-Cooper, manuscripts, notes, undated (Box 127, Folder 8)
      - Cole, Fay-Cooper, texts, correspondence, 1907-1909 (Box 127, Folder 9-11)
      - Cole, Fay-Cooper, texts I-XI, undated (Box 127, Folder 12)
      - Cole, Fay-Cooper, diams, field notes, undated (Box 127, Folder 13)
      - Cole, Fay-Cooper, Abra maps, undated (Box C)
  - Subseries 8: Town Field Notes and Photographs
    - Sub-subseries 1: Notes
      - Northern Luzon, maps, undated (Box 128, Folder 1)
      - Index to towns, undated (Box 128, Folder 2)
      - Abang, Abra, Fay-Cooper Cole, manuscript, undated (Box 128, Folder 3)
      - Abra, Ilocos Sur, Ilocos Norte, Fay-Cooper Cole, manuscripts, undated (Box 128, Folder 4)
      - Agismao, Tineg, Fay-Cooper Cole, Fred Eggan, manuscripts, undated (Box 128, Folder 5)
      - Amtuagan, Fay-Cooper Cole, manuscript, undated (Box 128, Folder 6)
      - Agawa, undated (Box 128, Folder 7)
      - Baac, Fay-Cooper Cole, Fred Eggan, manuscript, undated (Box 128, Folder 8)
      - Baac, San Quintin, undated (Box 128, Folder 9)
      - Baay, undated (Box 128, Folder 10)
      - Baay, Fay-Cooper Cole, manuscript, undated (Box 128, Folder 11)
      - Ba-ka-oc, Fay-Cooper Cole, manuscript, undated (Box 128, Folder 12)
      - Bakooc, undated (Box 128, Folder 13)
      - Balbalasang, undated (Box 128, Folder 14)
      - Balbalasang, kinship, undated (Box 128, Folder 15)
      - Ba-li-ga, Fay-Cooper Cole, manuscript, undated (Box 128, Folder 16)
      - Balili, correspondence, 1953 (Box 128, Folder 17)
      - Bangilo, undated (Box 128, Folder 18)
      - Bau-ian, undated (Box 128, Folder 19)
      - Besao, kinship, 1950 (Box 128, Folder 20)
      - Boklok, manuscript, 1955 (Box 128, Folder 21-22)
      - Bucay, Fay-Cooper Cole, manuscript, undated (Box 128, Folder 23)
      - Bugnay, kinship, undated (Box 128, Folder 24)
      - Bulilising, Fay-Cooper Cole, manuscript, undated (Box 128, Folder 25)
      - Buneg, undated (Box 128, Folder 26)
      - Buneg, Bacag, Lablabinag, Fay-Cooper Cole, manuscripts, undated (Box 128, Folder 27)
      - Daguioman, Tui, undated (Box 128, Folder 28)
      - Danac, Amti, Dao, undated (Box 128, Folder 29)
      - Danoc, Fay-Cooper Cole, undated (Box 128, Folder 30)
      - Danglas Municipality, Padangitan, undated (Box 128, Folder 31)
      - Dingras, undated (Box 128, Folder 32)
      - Gobang, Fay-Cooper Cole, manuscripts, undated (Box 128, Folder 33)
      - Lacub, undated (Box 128, Folder 34)
      - Lagangilang, Lagben barrio, undated (Box 128, Folder 35)
      - Lamao, Labaan, Lingey, Fay-Cooper Cole, manuscripts, undated (Box 128, Folder 36)
      - Langangilang, Fay-Cooper Cole, Fred Eggan, manuscript, undated (Box 128, Folder 37)
      - Lagayan, 1935 (Box 128, Folder 38)
      - Langiden, undated (Box 128, Folder 39)
      - Licuan, Fay-Cooper Cole, manuscript, undated (Box 128, Folder 40)
      - Likuan, Tinguian village, undated (Box 128, Folder 41)
      - Lingey, undated (Box 129, Folder 1)
      - Luba, diams, 1935 (Box 129, Folder 2)
      - Lu-lu-no, Fay-Cooper Cole, manuscript, undated (Box 129, Folder 3)
      - Lumaba, Villaviciosa, undated (Box 129, Folder 4)
      - Lumaba, Fay-Cooper Cole, manuscript, undated (Box 129, Folder 5)
      - Magueyepyep, undated (Box 129, Folder 6)
      - Manabo, 1934 (Box 129, Folder 7-9)
      - Manabo, Fay-Cooper Cole, manuscripts, undated (Box 129, Folder 10)
      - Mataragan, undated (Box 129, Folder 11)
      - Mulibcong, undated (Box 129, Folder 12)
      - Nagsingkauan, Ilocos Sur, undated (Box 129, Folder 13)
      - Patoc, Balaua, Tinguian villages, undated (Box 129, Folder 14)
      - Patoc, diams, stories, manuscripts, 1934-1935, 1955 (Box 129, Folder 15-18)
      - Patoc, manuscripts, 1935 (Box 130, Folder 1)
      - Patoc, Fay-Cooper Cole, manuscript, undated (Box 130, Folder 2)
      - Penarrubia, Tinguian village, undated (Box 130, Folder 3)
      - Sallapadan, undated (Box 130, Folder 4)
      - Sallapadan, Fay-Cooper Cole, manuscripts, undated (Box 130, Folder 5)
      - San Juan, undated (Box 130, Folder 6)
      - San Juan, Lagayan, Danglas, Fay-Cooper Cole, manuscripts, undated (Box 130, Folder 7)
      - San Quintan, undated (Box 130, Folder 8)
      - Santo Thomas, San Jose, Bucay, 1934 (Box 130, Folder 9)
      - Subosob, San Guillermo, Fay-Cooper Cole, manuscript, undated (Box 130, Folder 10)
      - Tiempo, undated (Box 130, Folder 11)
      - Tuba, diams, 1935 (Box 130, Folder 12)
      - Villaviciosa, Abra, Fay-Cooper Cole, manuscripts, undated (Box 130, Folder 13)
    - Sub-subseries 2: Photographs
      - [Cole, Fay-Cooper], scenes, landscapes, undated (Box 130, Folder 14)
      - [Cole, Fay-Cooper], objects, houses pots, undated (Box 130, Folder 15)
      - [Cole, Fay-Cooper], portraits, undated (Box 130, Folder 16-17)
      - [Cole, Fay-Cooper], portraits, undated (Box 131, Folder 1-2)
      - [Cole, Fay-Cooper], portraits with baskets, undated (Box 131, Folder 3)
      - [Cole, Fay-Cooper], work, rituals, undated (Box 131, Folder 4-6)
  - Subseries 9: Sagada
    - Sub-subseries 1: General
      - Sagada and Western Bontoc maps, notes, photograph, photographic negatives, undated (Box 131, Folder 7)
      - Projects, notes, undated (Box 131, Folder 8)
      - History, local neighbors, map, notes, undated (Box 131, Folder 9)
      - "The Culture of Sagada, an Igorot Village in the Mountain Province, Philippines, " manuscript, undated (Box 131, Folder 10)
      - "Sagada, " manuscript, notes, undated (Box 131, Folder 11)
      - "Social Organization among the Igorots of Sagada and Their Neighbors in the Mountain Province, Northern Luzon, " Ninth Pacific Science Congress, Bangkok, Thailand, manuscripts, correspondence, notes, November 18-December 9, 1957 (Box 132, Folder 1)
      - Reprints, 1941-1954 (Box 132, Folder 2)
      - Eggan, Dorothy, correspondence, 1949-1950 (Box 132, Folder 3)
      - Eggan, Fred and Dorothy Eggan, correspondence, 1949-1950 (Box 132, Folder 4)
      - Eggan, Fred and Alfredo Pacyaya, genealogical charts, undated (Box 132, Folder 5)
      - Aclop, Leonard, M., "Reports to Dr. Fred Eggan, " manuscripts, correspondence, notes, 1955-1957 (Box 132, Folder 6)
      - Barton, Roy F., photographs, undated (Box 132, Folder 7)
      - An Engineer's Dream, " manuscript, correspondence, newsletter, 1954 (Box 132, Folder 8)
      - Pacyaya, Alfredo, correspondence, 1950-1959 (Box 132, Folder 9)
      - Pacyaya, Alfredo, autobiography, manuscript, correspondence, c.1956 (Box 132, Folder 10-11)
      - Pacyaya, Alfredo, Chicago, Fulbright, Guggenheim, manuscripts, correspondence, 1955-1956 (Box 132, Folder 12)
      - Pacyaya, Alfredo, "Answers to Miscellaneous Questions, " manuscript, undated (Box 133, Folder 1)
      - Scott, William H., correspondence, 1954-1959 (Box 133, Folder 2)
      - Scott, William H., Maleng-Abra trip, notes, 1955 (Box 133, Folder 3)
      - Scott, William H., reprints, 1958-1974 (Box 133, Folder 4)
      - Sagada Postboy, newsletter of Saint Mary's Junior College, Sagada, 1968 (Box 133, Folder 5)
      - Voss, Joachim H., correspondence, photographs, 1981 (Box 133, Folder 6)
      - Voss, Joachim H., "Capitalist Penetration and Local Resistance, " Ph.D. dissertation, University of Toronto, 1983 (Box 133, Folder 7-9)
      - Wilson, Laurence L., correspondence, photographs, undated (Box 133, Folder 10)
    - Sub-subseries 2: Linguistics
      - Cognate word lists, notes, undated (Box 133, Folder 11)
      - Manuscript, notes, undated (Box 133, Folder 12)
      - Vocabulary, notes, undated (Box 133, Folder 13)
      - "Comparative Lexical List for Northern Luzon, "undated (Box 133, Folder 14)
      - Scott, William Henry, dialects and sound shifts in Mountain Province, manuscripts, notes, 1956 (Box 133, Folder 15)
      - Scott, William Henry, Sagada and Bontok phonetics, undated (Box 133, Folder 16)
      - Scott, William Henry, reprint, undated (Box 133, Folder 17)
    - Sub-subseries 3: Economics and Material Culture
      - Agriculture, rice crop, granary, notes, undated (Box 134, Folder 1)
      - Rice raising, Alfredo Pacyaya, notes, undated (Box 134, Folder 2)
      - Economic relations, agriculture, hunting, notes, undated (Box 134, Folder 3)
      - Population and agricultural statistics, notes, undated (Box 134, Folder 4)
      - Bauco, notes, undated (Box 134, Folder 5)
      - Houses, ceremonies for house building, and for a burnt house, notes, undated (Box 134, Folder 6)
      - House types, Cordillera house, notes, undated (Box 134, Folder 7)
      - Instruments, music, songs, notes, undated (Box 134, Folder 8)
      - Manufactures, weapons, pipes, weaving, notes, undated (Box 134, Folder 9)
      - Measures, color, notes, undated (Box 134, Folder 10)
      - Dress, ornaments, beauty, notes, undated (Box 134, Folder 11)
      - Pigs, chickens, notes, undated (Box 134, Folder 12)
      - Cave burials, correspondence, photographs, 1953-1958 (Box 134, Folder 13)
      - Birket-Smith, Kaj, manuscripts, correspondence, reprint, 1952-1955 (Box 134, Folder 14)
      - Pacyaya, Alfredo, "Economic Life, " manuscript, notes, undated (Box 134, Folder 15)
      - Pacyaya, Alfredo, "The Institution of Gawat in Sagada, " "The Obbo (reciprocal labor) in Sagada, " manuscript, correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 134, Folder 16)
      - Pacyaya, Alfredo, "When a House Burns Down, " manuscript, correspondence, 1955 (Box 134, Folder 17)
      - Scott, William H., "Growing Rice in Sagada, " manuscript, reprint, 1963 (Box 134, Folder 18)
      - Scott, William H., "A Report on Upland Rice in the Mountain Province for Dr. Harold Conklin, " manuscript, 1956 (Box 134, Folder 19)
      - Scott, William H., house burning, diary, undated (Box 134, Folder 20)
    - Sub-subseries 4: Politics
      - Law, disputes, notes, undated (Box 134, Folder 21)
      - Peace pact trade, notes, 1958 (Box 134, Folder 22)
      - Political organization, notes, undated (Box 134, Folder 23)
      - Rock fights, notes, clippings, 1937-1948 (Box 134, Folder 24)
    - Sub-subseries 5: Social Structure
      - Day-ap, origin, order, Pekdasin, Pinading, notes, undated (Box 134, Folder 25)
      - Death in childbirth, notes, undated (Box 134, Folder 26)
      - Genealogical charts, notes, undated (Box 134, Folder 27)
      - Kinship terminology and behavior, manuscript, notes, undated (Box 134, Folder 28)
      - Life cycle, manuscripts, notes, undated (Box 134, Folder 29-30)
      - Life cycle, childhood, games, notes, undated (Box 134, Folder 31)
      - Life cycle, marriage, notes, 1954-1956 (Box 134, Folder 32)
      - Life cycle, marriage, death, burial, notes, 1950 (Box 135, Folder 1)
      - Main families, notes, undated (Box 135, Folder 2)
      - Divorce and adultery, notes, undated (Box 135, Folder 3)
      - Inheritance, notes, undated (Box 135, Folder 4)
      - Social classes, notes, undated (Box 135, Folder 5)
      - "Social Structure of the Sagada Igorots, " manuscripts, correspondence, reprint, 1958-1963 (Box 135, Folder 6-7)
      - Pacyaya, Alfredo, genealogies, Magalgalit family, customs, manuscripts, correspondence, notes, 1973-1974 (Box 135, Folder 8)
      - Pacyaya, Alfredo, social and economic life, correspondence, notes, clippings, 1955-1959 (Box 135, Folder 9)
      - Pacyaya, Alfredo, Bilig dap-ay, manuscripts, correspondence, 1960-1961 (Box 135, Folder 10)
      - Pacyaya, Alfredo, dap-ays and main families, notes, undated (Box 135, Folder 11)
      - Pacyaya, Alfredo, kinship terms, notes, undated (Box 135, Folder 12)
      - Pacyaya, Alfredo, "Amtadao and Tetepan, " manuscript, notes, undated (Box 135, Folder 13)
      - Pacyaya, Alfredo, "Life in a Sagada Dap-ay, " manuscript, correspondence, notes, 1951-1952 (Box 135, Folder 14)
      - Pacyaya, Alfredo, "Life in a Sagada Ebgan, " manuscript, correspondence, clippings, 1951-1972 (Box 135, Folder 15)
      - Pacyaya, Alfredo, "Symbolism in Sagada, " "Sagada Sacred Trees, " manuscripts, correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 135, Folder 16)
      - Scott, William H., "Boyhood in Sagada, " correspondence, reprint, 1958-1959 (Box 135, Folder 17)
      - Scott, William H., courtship and marriage, correspondence, notes, 1964 (Box 135, Folder 18)
      - Scott, William H., life cycle, toilet training, dapay, notes, 1954-1956 (Box 135, Folder 19)
      - Wilson, Laurence L., "The Bontoc Ato System, " tables, 1952 (Box 135, Folder 20)
    - Sub-subseries 6: Religion
      - "Aníto, Spirit, " manuscript, undated (Box 136, Folder 1)
      - "Apoi ritual, " manuscript, undated (Box 136, Folder 2)
      - Bayang ceremony, notes, undated (Box 136, Folder 3)
      - "The Bawi, " manuscript, map, undated (Box 136, Folder 4)
      - Begnas ceremony, manuscripts, notes, undated (Box 136, Folder 5-6)
      - Ceremonies, notes, undated (Box 136, Folder 7-8)
      - "The Ceremonial Calendar, " manuscript, notes, clipping, undated (Box 136, Folder 9)
      - "Ceremonial Organization and Reorganization in Sagada, " Seminar on Process in Religious Organization, manuscripts, May 25, 1959 (Box 136, Folder 10)
      - "Ceremonies at the Bawi in Dodo-owan, " manuscript, notes, undated (Box 136, Folder 11)
      - Dangtey ceremony, manuscripts, notes, 1955-1961 (Box 136, Folder 12)
      - "The Dangtey Ceremony, " manuscript, undated (Box 136, Folder 13)
      - "Dirge for the Dead, " text, translation, undated (Box 136, Folder 14)
      - Field notebooks, notes, manuscripts, 1957-1958 (Box 136, Folder 15)
      - Interpretations, notes, undated (Box 136, Folder 16)
      - Magic, poison, witchcraft, notes, undated (Box 136, Folder 17)
      - Meat distribution, notes, undated (Box 136, Folder 18)
      - "Ob-ob ceremony, " manuscript, notes, undated (Box 136, Folder 19)
      - Origin myths, notes, undated (Box 136, Folder 20)
      - Origins of Dap-ay, calling the soul of a sick person, interlinear translations, notes, undated (Box 136, Folder 21)
      - Otop ceremony, notes, undated (Box 136, Folder 22)
      - Patpatayan Pakde, notes, photograph, clipping, 1951 (Box 136, Folder 23)
      - `The Sacred Grove, '" manuscript, notes, undated (Box 136, Folder 24)
      - Pinading, sacred grove, anítos, manuscript, notes, clipping, 1949 (Box 136, Folder 25)
      - Pisang ceremony, manuscripts, undated (Box 136, Folder 26)
      - Prayer for kuba (flood), Amolo ceremony, notes, undated (Box 136, Folder 27)
      - Rituals, cosmology, priests, notes, undated (Box 136, Folder 28)
      - Takba and related ceremonies (Box 137, Folder 1)
      - "The Wangé Ceremony, " manuscript, notes, undated (Box 137, Folder 2)
      - From Birth to Adolescence, " manuscript, reprint, 1965 (Box 137, Folder 3)
      - Reformation and Accommodation among the Igorots of Mountain Province, Northern Luzon, " manuscript, correspondence, 1962 (Box 137, Folder 4)
      - Eggan, Fred, and Alfredo Pacyaya, manuscripts, correspondence, notes, 1956-1960 (Box 137, Folder 5)
      - Baguio Religious Acculturative Conference, Baguio City, report, January 3-5, 1958 (Box 137, Folder 6)
      - Barton, Roy F., notes, undated (Box 137, Folder 7)
      - "Legends Recorded by Students in the Mission High School, Sagada, Mountain Province, " manuscripts, 1950 (Box 137, Folder 8)
      - Pacyaya, Alfredo, ceremonies, manuscripts, correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 137, Folder 9)
      - Its Significance and Role, " manuscript, correspondence, notes, 1975 (Box 137, Folder 10)
      - Pacyaya, Alfredo, "Classification of Totems in Sagada, " "Old Rites and Ceremonials of the Bontoc Mamaka, " manuscripts, correspondence, 1973 (Box 137, Folder 11)
      - Pacyaya, Alfredo, "The Sagada Dangtey-Pisang of 1961, " manuscript, correspondence, photographs, 1959-1962 (Box 137, Folder 12)
      - Pacyaya, Alfredo, "Daing di Palis, " manuscripts, 1956 (Box 137, Folder 13)
      - Pacyaya, Alfredo, "A Dictionary of Religious Terms and Ceremonies as Used in Sagada, " manuscript, undated (Box 137, Folder 14)
      - Pacyaya, Alfredo, Dodo'owan ceremony, ritual of old men, transcripts, correspondence, student papers, 1955-1958 (Box 137, Folder 15)
      - Pacyaya, Alfredo, "Kubá ceremony for stopping storms, " manuscript, notes, undated (Box 137, Folder 16)
      - Pacyaya, Alfredo, "Nan I-Til, " manuscript, undated (Box 137, Folder 17)
      - Pacyaya, Alfredo, "Native Dances of Western Bontoc, " notes, undated (Box 137, Folder 18)
      - Pacyaya, Alfredo, rituals of death, correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 137, Folder 19)
      - Pacyaya, Alfredo and Fred Eggan, "A Sagada Igorot Ballad, " manuscripts, correspondence, reprint, notes, 1952-1953 (Box 137, Folder 20)
      - Scott, William H., Begnas ceremony, notes, 1954-1956 (Box 137, Folder 21)
      - Scott, William H., doctors, curing, newsletter, 1962 (Box 137, Folder 22)
      - Scott, William H., Eduardo Bete, religion, manuscript, correspondence, 1959 (Box 137, Folder 23)
      - Scott, William H., Langit ceremony, notes, 1955-1956 (Box 137, Folder 24)
      - Scott, William H., religion, correspondence, notes, 1954-1965 (Box 137, Folder 25)
      - Scott, William H., "The Descendants of Maym-es Magalgalit of Demang, Sagada, " "Families of Dap-ay Banowao, Demang, Sagada, " manuscripts, undated (Box 137, Folder 26)
      - Scott, William H., "The Legend of Biag, " manuscript, 1963 (Box 137, Folder 27)
      - Scott, William H., "Native Names of the Months in Payeo, Besao, " manuscript, 1955 (Box 137, Folder 28)
      - Scott, William H., Pális, Dawis, manuscript, 1954 (Box 137, Folder 29)
      - Scott, William H., "Prayer Index, "undated (Box 137, Folder 30)
      - Scott, William H., "A Report on the Mountain Province Seasonal Calendar, " manuscript, reprint, clipping, 1947-1958 (Box 137, Folder 31)
      - Scott, William H., "Sagada Pantheon, " manuscript, notes, undated (Box 137, Folder 32)
      - Scott, William H., "Special Harvest, " notes, 1956 (Box 137, Folder 33)
  - Subseries 10: Card Files
    - Notes and field notes, undated (Box 138)
    - Patok census, undated (Box 138)
    - Bibliography, undated (Box 139)
    - Comparative word list, undated (Box 139)
    - Flora, vocabulary, undated (Box 139)
    - Tinguian vocabulary, notes, undated (Box 139)
    - Vocabulary, undated (Box 140)
  - Subseries 11: Central Philippines
    - "Land-use Regions of the Bikol Area, " map, undated (Box 141, Folder 1)
    - Philippine interpersonal relations, manuscripts, correspondence, 1958-1960 (Box 141, Folder 2)
    - Notes, undated (Box 141, Folder 3)
    - "Philippine Social Structure, " manuscripts, undated (Box 141, Folder 4)
    - The Politics of Occidental Mindoro, reprint, 1965 (Box 141, Folder 5)